A Register of the Records of the Russkaia sredniaia shkola (Paris, France)Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Russkaia sredniaia shkola (Paris, France) Records
1920-1968
2008C77
Russkaia sredniaia shkola (Paris, France)
29 microfilm reels 4.35 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
These papers consist of the records of the Russkaia sredniaia shkola v Parizhe, the Russian Secondary school in Paris, which operated from 1920-1961, and graduated more than 1,200 students during that time. A major educational centre for children of Russian émigrés, the school was originally opened with the support of the Russian Consulate in 1920, and through the initiative of M. A. Maklakova and V. B. Nedachin.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
The entire collection is available on Microfilm
Location of Original Materials
Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers consist of the records of the Russkaia sredniaia shkola v Parizhe, the Russian Secondary school in Paris, which operated from 1920-1961, and graduated more than 1,200 students during that time. A major educational centre for children of Russian émigrés, the school was originally opened with the support of the Russian Consulate in 1920, and through the initiative of M. A. Maklakova and V. B. Nedachin. The school soon began operating independently, while receiving support from the Obshchestvo prosveshcheniia detei bezhentsov iz Rossii. In 1928, it received generous contributions, including real estate, from Lidiia Pavlovna Deterdling, which allowed it to operate for the following decades in the same location. Teachers of the Russian secondary school in Paris included B. A. Durov, G. A. Lozinskii, S. G. Popich, E. A. Sham'e, P. P. Sakharov, K. D. Starynkevich, and P. P. Troitskii.
As a major educational centre, the Russkaia sredniaia shkola v Parizhe received applications from children of Russian émigrés of different social backgrounds, including Grand Duke Vladimir Kirillovich, Konstantin Bagration-Mukhranskii, Tikhon Nikolaevich Kulikovskii, Nicholas Zernov, and others.
The Office file consists of detailed organizational files, including attendance records, applications, correspondence, employment files, grade reports, financial records, historical documents, lists of students and teachers, minutes, reports, and student files, which contain more than 1,800 applications for admission. The Photographs show prints of pupils and teachers between the years 1928 and 1949.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series: Office file, Photographs, and Oversize file
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the online catalog.
Nedachin, Vasilii Petrovich.; Obshchestvo prosveshcheniia detei bezhentsov iz Rossii.; Romanov, House of.; Russians--France--Paris.; Russkaia sredniaia shkola v Parizhe.; Photographs.
Collection Contents
- Office file, 1920-1997 and undated. (Box 1)
  Address book, announcements, applications, attendance records, bylaws, certificates, concert programs, correspondence, diplomas, employment file, examinations, financial documents, grade reports, instructions, insurance policies, inventory, lists, memoranda, minutes, notes, pamphlets, petitions, receipts, reports, statutes, student records
  - Address book, undated (Folder 1: 1)
  - Applications
    - Entrance
      - 1923-1929 and undated (Folder 1: 2)
      - 1930-1959 (Folder 1: 3)
    - Examinations
      - 1923-1949 and undated (Folder 1: 4)
      - 1950-1961 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Attendance records, 1923-1926 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Certificates
    - General
      - 1916-1924 and undated (Folder 1: 7)
      - 1925-1961 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - Graduation., See also Oversize file
      - General, 1921; 1929 and undated (Folder 2: 2)
      - A (Folder 2: 3)
      - B (Folder 2: 4)
      - C (Folder 2: 5)
      - D (Folder 2: 6)
      - E (Folder 2: 7)
      - F (Folder 2: 8)
      - G (Folder 2: 9)
      - I (Folder 2: 10)
      - K (Folder 2: 11)
      - L (Folder 2: 12)
      - M (Box-folder 3: 1)
      - N (Folder 3: 2)
      - O (Folder 3: 3)
      - P (Folder 3: 4)
      - R (Folder 3: 5)
      - S (Folder 3: 6)
      - T (Folder 3: 7)
      - U (Folder 3: 8)
      - V (Folder 3: 9)
      - Z (Folder 3: 10)
    - Scholarships, 1933-1960 and undated (Folder 3: 11)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1961 and undated
    - General
      - Undated (Folder 3: 12)
      - 1920-1928 (Folder 3: 13)
      - 1930-1939 (Folder 3: 14)
      - 1940-1949 (Box-folder 4: 1)
      - 1950-1959 (Folder 4: 2)
      - 1960-1961 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Academie de Paris, 1926-1961 and undated (Folder 4: 4)
    - Rostovtseva, Ol'ga Nikolaevna, 1933 (Folder 4: 5)
    - Rossiiskii Zemsko-gorodskoi komitet pomoshchi rossiiskim grazhdanam za granitsei, 1952-1961 and undated (Folder 4: 6)
  - Employment file, 1924-1931 and undated (Folder 4: 7)
  - Financial documents, 1920-1961 and undated
    - Annual reports, incomplete, 1952-1961 (Folder 4: 8)
    - Charitable ball documents, 1935-1965 and undated. (Folder 4: 9)
      Includes acknowledgements, announcements, appeals, donation lists, programs, tickets, and related correspondence
    - Exhibit receipts, 1949 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Heating expenses, 1939-1951 and undated (Folder 5: 2)
    - Meal expenses, 1942-1952 (Folder 5: 3)
    - Receipts
      - 1920-1929 and undated (Folder 5: 4)
      - 1931 (Folder 5: 5)
      - 1932 (Folder 5: 6)
      - 1950-1954 (Folder 5: 7)
      - 1955 (Folder 5: 8)
      - 1956 (Folder 5: 9)
      - 1957-1958 (Box-folder 6: 1)
      - 1959-1961 (Folder 6: 2)
    - Salary expenses
      - 1953 January - 1954 December, incomplete (Folder 6: 3)
      - 1955 January – 1959 June, incomplete (Folder 6: 4)
    - Student accounts (Folder 6: 5)
    - Treasurer's book
      - 1921-1937. (Folder 6: 6)
        Includes list of students from October 1921 through 1937 by grade
      - 1938-1939 (Box-folder 7: 1)
      - 1937-1943 (Folder 7: 2)
      - 1943-1949 (Folder 7: 3)
      - 1949-1952 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Grade reports
    - General
      - General (Folder 7: 5)
      - Monthly, 1957-1958 and undated (Folder 7: 6)
    - Undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - 1920-1921 (Folder 8: 2)
    - 1922-1923 (Folder 8: 3)
    - 1923-1924 (Folder 8: 4)
    - 1924-1925 (Folder 8: 5)
    - 1925-1926 (Folder 8: 6)
    - 1926-1927 (Folder 8: 7)
    - 1927-1928 (Folder 8: 8)
    - 1928-1929 (Folder 8: 9)
    - 1929-1930 (Folder 8: 10)
    - 1930-1931 (Folder 8: 11)
    - 1931-1932 (Folder 8: 12)
    - 1932-1933 (Folder 8: 13)
    - 1933-1934 (Folder 8: 14)
    - 1934-1935 (Folder 8: 15)
    - 1935-1936 (Folder 8: 16)
    - 1936-1937 (Folder 8: 17)
    - 1937-1938 (Folder 8: 18)
    - 1938-1939 (Folder 8: 19)
    - 1939-1940 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 9: 2)
    - 1941-1942 (Folder 9: 3)
    - 1942-1943 (Folder 9: 4)
    - 1943-1944 (Folder 9: 5)
    - 1944-1945 (Folder 9: 6)
    - 1945-1946 (Folder 9: 7)
    - 1946-1947 (Folder 9: 8)
    - 1947-1948 (Folder 9: 9)
    - 1948-1949 (Folder 9: 10)
    - 1949-1950 (Folder 9: 11)
    - 1950-1951 (Folder 9: 12)
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 9: 13)
    - 1952-1953 (Folder 9: 14)
    - 1953-1954 (Folder 9: 15)
    - 1954-1955 (Folder 9: 16)
    - 1955-1956 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - 1956-1957 (Folder 10: 2)
    - 1957-1958 (Folder 10: 3)
    - 1958-1960 (Folder 10: 4)
  - Historical documents, 1920-97 and undated
    - General, 1920-1936 and undated (Folder 10: 5)
    - Announcements, 1920 and undated (Folder 10: 6)
    - Concert programs, 1928-1930 (Folder 10: 7)
    - Curriculum, 1921-1961 and undated (Folder 10: 8)
    - Diplomas - Popich, Sergei Georgievich (Folder 10: 9)
    - Examinations and reports
      - General, 1920-1943 and undated (Folder 10: 10)
      - Topics for translation, 1956-1959 and undated (Folder 10: 11)
    - Instructions for teachers, 1937 and undated (Folder 10: 12)
    - K desiatiletiiu russkoi srednei shkoly v Parizhe, 1930. (Folder 10: 13)
      Printed copies
    - "Polozhenie o russkoi srednei shkole v Parizhe,", 1931 and undated. (Folder 10: 14)
      Typescript
    - Rules, Undated (Folder 10: 15)
    - Printed matter
      - General, 1930-1953 and undated (Folder 10: 16)
      - Clippings, 1924-1965 and undated (Folder 10: 17)
  - Insurance policies, 1920-1951 and undated (Folder 10: 18)
  - Lists
    - Graduates, 1920-1961 (Folder 10: 19)
    - Staff, 1938-1951 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Students, 1920-1960.; See also Financial documents/Treasuers's book (Folder 11: 2)
    - Teachers, 1933-1951 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Minutes of meetings
    - 1921-1930 (Folder 11: 4)
    - 1931-1937 (Folder 11: 5)
    - 1938-1941 (Folder 11: 6)
    - 1942-1946 (Folder 11: 7)
    - 1947-1955 (Folder 11: 8)
  - Obshchestvo byvshkikh vospitannikov russkoi srednei shkoly v Parizhe
    - General (Folder 11: 9)
    - Announcements, memoranda, 1959-1975 and undated (Folder 11: 10)
    - "Biuleten'", 1927 (Folder 11: 11)
    - Bylaws, 1966 and undated (Folder 11: 12)
    - Correspondence, 1927-1965 and undated (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Financial documents
      - Fundraising, 1955-1971 and undated (Folder 12: 2)
      - Receipts, 1927-1968 and undated (Folder 12: 3)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1927-1929 (Folder 12: 4)
    - Petitions, 1928-1929 (Folder 12: 5)
    - Reunions, 1963-1970 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Parents committee documents, 1951-1952 (Folder 12: 7)
  - Student records
    - Abramova, Nataliia (Folder 12: 8)
    - Achkasov, Viktor (Folder 12: 9)
    - Achkasova, Elizaveta (Folder 12: 10)
    - Adamovich, Mikhail (Folder 12: 11)
    - Afanas'eva, Tatiana (Folder 12: 12)
    - Afonin, Sergei (Folder 12: 13)
    - Afrosimova, Vera (Folder 12: 14)
    - Agafonova, Elena (Folder 12: 15)
    - Agap'eva, Evgeniia (Folder 12: 16)
    - Agrikolianskii, Mr. (Folder 12: 17)
    - Aikanova, Nina (Folder 12: 18)
    - Aizenshtat, Iuliia (Folder 12: 19)
    - Akhmud-Zade, Ardashiva (Folder 12: 20)
    - Akhmud-Zade, Asia (Folder 12: 21)
    - Akimov, Lev (Folder 12: 22)
    - Akimov, Mikhail (Folder 12: 23)
    - Akimova, Tat'iana (Folder 12: 24)
    - Akopov, Georgii (Folder 12: 25)
    - Aksenova, Tat'iana (Folder 12: 26)
    - Akvisov, Vladimir (Folder 12: 27)
    - Alafuzov, Ivan (Folder 12: 28)
    - Alatyrtsev, Igor' (Folder 12: 29)
    - Al'brind, Vadim (Folder 12: 30)
    - Alekhin, Ivan (Folder 12: 31)
    - Aleksandrov, Igor' (Folder 12: 32)
    - Aleksandrov, Kirill (Folder 12: 33)
    - Aleksandrov, Leonid (Folder 12: 34)
    - Aleksandrov, Irina (Folder 12: 35)
    - Aleksandrov, Nina (Folder 12: 36)
    - Aleksandrov, Tat'iana (Folder 12: 37)
    - Aleksandrov-Dol'nik, Vladimir (Folder 12: 38)
    - Alekseeva, Liliana (Folder 12: 39)
    - Aleksinskii, Vladimir (Folder 12: 40)
    - Alfago, Vicente (Folder 12: 41)
    - Alferov, Anatolii (Folder 12: 42)
    - Al'ianaki, Leonid (Folder 12: 43)
    - Alieva, Liudmila (Folder 12: 44)
    - Alieva, Mariia (Folder 12: 45)
    - Alieva, Zoia (Folder 12: 46)
    - Alisova, Elena (Folder 12: 47)
    - Al'shvang, Nina (Folder 12: 48)
    - Amilakhvari, Nikolai (Folder 12: 49)
    - Aminov, A. (Folder 12: 50)
    - Anderson, Georgii (Folder 12: 51)
    - Andreev, Dmitrii (Folder 12: 52)
    - Andreev, Konstantin (Folder 12: 53)
    - Andreev, Valentin (Folder 12: 54)
    - Andreev, Viktor (Folder 12: 55)
    - Andreeva, Vera (Folder 12: 56)
    - Andrianova, Aleksandra (Folder 12: 57)
    - Androvich, Nikolai (Folder 12: 58)
    - Anichkov, Iurii (Folder 12: 59)
    - Anisimov, Georgii (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Annenkova, Anna (Folder 13: 2)
    - Anosov, C. (Folder 13: 3)
    - Anosov, C., Elizaveta (Folder 13: 4)
    - Antonenko, Mavra (Folder 13: 5)
    - Antonov, Daniil (Folder 13: 6)
    - Antonov, Georgii (Folder 13: 7)
    - Antonov, Igor' (Folder 13: 8)
    - Amfriev, Nikolai (Folder 13: 9)
    - Apparovich, Aleksandr (Folder 13: 10)
    - Aprelev, Petr (Folder 13: 11)
    - Arabei, Nikolai (Folder 13: 12)
    - Arafelov, Mikhail (Folder 13: 13)
    - Anendarov, Georgii (Folder 13: 14)
    - Arkhangel'skaia, Mirra (Folder 13: 15)
    - Arkhipov, Georgii, and Iriina (Folder 13: 16)
    - Artsimovich, Mikhail (Folder 13: 17)
    - Asadchikova, Marina (Folder 13: 18)
    - Asheberg, Nikolai (Folder 13: 19)
    - Aslanova, Nadezhda (Folder 13: 20)
    - Assanovich, Lev (Folder 13: 21)
    - Asseev, Andrei (Folder 13: 22)
    - Astaf'ev, Grigorii (Folder 13: 23)
    - Atsakhovich, Valentin (Folder 13: 24)
    - Augenblik, Vladimir (Folder 13: 25)
    - Auerbakh, Nina (Folder 13: 26)
    - Auzit-Shvarts, Monika (Folder 13: 27)
    - Avanesov, Ivan (Folder 13: 28)
    - Avdeev, Georgii (Folder 13: 29)
    - Avdeev, Ivan (Folder 13: 30)
    - Avis, Jacqueline (Folder 13: 31)
    - Babadin, Boris (Folder 13: 32)
    - Bagdasarian, Vagan (Folder 13: 33)
    - Bagration-Mukhranskii, Konstantin (Folder 13: 34)
    - Bagrianovskaia, Aleksandra (Folder 13: 35)
    - Bagrianovskii, Georgii (Folder 13: 36)
    - Baier, Kira (Folder 13: 37)
    - Bakhrakh, Aleksandr (Folder 13: 38)
    - Baklanov, Boris (Folder 13: 39)
    - Balandin, Fedor (Folder 13: 40)
    - Balandin, Mikhail and Vladimir (Folder 13: 41)
    - Balash, Nadezhda (Folder 13: 42)
    - Balashev, Andrei (Folder 13: 43)
    - Balin, Valentin (Folder 13: 44)
    - Baranova, Irina (Folder 13: 45)
    - Baranovskaia, Evgeniia (Folder 13: 46)
    - Baranovskaia, Mariia (Folder 13: 47)
    - Baranovskaia, Nataliia (Folder 13: 48)
    - Baratova, Marina (Folder 13: 49)
    - Barn, Ol'ga (Folder 13: 50)
    - Barnev, El'mar (Folder 13: 51)
    - Barnev, Petr (Folder 13: 52)
    - Barneva, Ol'ga (Folder 13: 53)
    - Barsukova, Erika (Folder 13: 54)
    - Barteneva, Anastasiia (Folder 13: 55)
    - Bartl', Khil'da (Folder 13: 56)
    - Barto, Nikolai (Folder 13: 57)
    - Barthosh, Aleksandr (Folder 13: 58)
    - Bashanov, Viktor (Folder 13: 59)
    - Bashkirov, Boris (Folder 13: 60)
    - Bashkirova, Zoia (Folder 13: 61)
    - Bashkevich, Pavel (Folder 13: 62)
    - Batulina, Nataliia (Folder 13: 63)
    - Batulina, Tat'iana (Folder 13: 64)
    - Batishcheva, Vera (Folder 13: 65)
    - Bazhenko, Mikhail (Folder 13: 66)
    - Bazilevich, Igor' (Folder 13: 67)
    - Bebko, Vladislav (Folder 13: 68)
    - Bek-Sofiev, Igor' (Folder 13: 69)
    - Bekeeva, Dzhennet (Folder 13: 70)
    - Bekel', Konstantin (Folder 13: 71)
    - Belaia, Evgeniia (Folder 13: 72)
    - Belavenets, Elena (Folder 13: 73)
    - Bel'chenko, Apollinarii (Folder 13: 74)
    - Bel'chenko, Oleg (Folder 13: 75)
    - Bel'chenko, Valentin (Folder 13: 76)
    - Belevskaia-Zhurovskaia, Elena (Folder 13: 77)
    - Beliaev, Vladimir (Folder 13: 78)
    - Beliaeva, Nataliia (Folder 13: 79)
    - Beliakov, Petr (Folder 13: 80)
    - Belikov, Georgii (Folder 13: 81)
    - Belikov, Sergei (Folder 13: 82)
    - Belinko, Kseniia (Folder 13: 83)
    - Bellinger, Henry (Folder 13: 84)
    - Belobedov, Boris (Folder 13: 85)
    - Belogovskaia, Nataliia (Folder 13: 86)
    - Beloklintsev, Troadii (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Beloshitskaia, Galina (Folder 14: 2)
    - Belostotskaia, Miula (Folder 14: 3)
    - Belousovich, Andrei (Folder 14: 4)
    - Bel't, Boris (Folder 14: 5)
    - Bel't, Mark (Folder 14: 6)
    - Belyi, Igor' (Folder 14: 7)
    - Belyi, Vsevolod (Folder 14: 8)
    - Benigsen, Pavel (Folder 14: 9)
    - Benigsen, Sergei (Folder 14: 10)
    - Ben'kovskaia, Kseniia (Folder 14: 11)
    - Ben'kovskii, Andrei (Folder 14: 12)
    - Ben'kovskii, Iaroslav (Folder 14: 13)
    - Benua, Roman (Folder 14: 14)
    - Berdiukova, Anna (Folder 14: 15)
    - Berens, Liudmila (Folder 14: 16)
    - Berezova, Svetlana (Folder 14: 17)
    - Berg, Dmitrii (Folder 14: 18)
    - Berner, Vsevolod (Folder 14: 19)
    - Bernshtain, Evgeniia (Folder 14: 20)
    - Bernshtain, Margarita (Folder 14: 21)
    - Berting, Brian Sydney (Folder 14: 22)
    - Bertman, Thierry (Folder 14: 23)
    - Bertrand, Irine (Folder 14: 24)
    - Beshenova, Nina (Folder 14: 25)
    - Bestuzheva, Nadezhda (Folder 14: 26)
    - Bezenval', Georgii (Folder 14: 27)
    - Bezenval', Valentina (Folder 14: 28)
    - Bezsmertnyi-Brusilovskii, Lev (Folder 14: 29)
    - Bezsomov, Andrei (Folder 14: 30)
    - Blatner, Andrei (Folder 14: 31)
    - Bobrovskii, Aleksandr (Folder 14: 32)
    - Bobryshev, Aleksandr (Folder 14: 33)
    - Bodisko, Marina (Folder 14: 34)
    - Boganova, Tat'iana (Folder 14: 35)
    - Bogdan, Boris (Folder 14: 36)
    - Bogdan, Georgii (Folder 14: 37)
    - Bogul', Dmitrii (Folder 14: 38)
    - Bogul', Tamara (Folder 14: 39)
    - Boiko, Konstantin (Folder 14: 40)
    - Boldyreva, Elena (Folder 14: 41)
    - Bolotova, Nadezhda (Folder 14: 42)
    - Bialonovich, Evgeniia (Folder 14: 43)
    - Bibikov, Vladimir (Folder 14: 44)
    - Bibikova, Nataliia (Folder 14: 45)
    - Bil'derling, Ekaterina (Folder 14: 46)
    - Bil'derling, Georgii (Folder 14: 47)
    - Bil't, Mark (Folder 14: 48)
    - Bitner, Nina (Folder 14: 49)
    - Bizerov, Zhivko (Folder 14: 50)
    - Blinovich, Boris (Folder 14: 51)
    - Bliumental', Ol'ga (Folder 14: 52)
    - Blomering, Elena (Folder 14: 53)
    - Boborykin, Daniil (Folder 14: 54)
    - Boborykin, Nikita (Folder 14: 55)
    - Boborykina, Nataliia (Folder 14: 56)
    - Bobrinskaia, Mariia (Folder 14: 57)
    - Bobrishchev, Sergei (Folder 14: 58)
    - Bobrova, Elena (Folder 14: 59)
    - Bobrovskaia, Irina (Folder 14: 60)
    - Bobrovskii, Nikolai (Folder 14: 61)
    - Bobryshev, Aleksandr (Folder 14: 62)
    - Bezkhlebova, Apolinariia (Folder 14: 63)
    - Bezsmertnyi, Irina (Folder 14: 64)
    - Bocharnikova, Tamara (Folder 14: 65)
    - Bochanov, Nikolai (Folder 14: 66)
    - Bodlo, Zinaida (Folder 14: 67)
    - Bogaevskaia, Nina (Folder 14: 68)
    - Bogaevskii, Boris (Folder 14: 69)
    - Bogaevskii, Georgii (Folder 14: 70)
    - Bogaevskii, Il'ia (Folder 14: 71)
    - Bogdanova, Nataliia (Folder 14: 72)
    - Bogdanova, Sofiia (Folder 14: 73)
    - Bogoiavlenskaia, Galina (Folder 14: 74)
    - Bogomolova, Nadezhda (Folder 14: 75)
    - Boguslavskaia, Nataliia (Folder 14: 76)
    - Boguslavskii, Mr. (Folder 14: 77)
    - Boiko, Konstantin (Folder 14: 78)
    - Boiko, Mikhail (Folder 14: 79)
    - Boiko, Vladimir (Folder 14: 80)
    - Bokil'on, Aleksandr (Folder 14: 81)
    - Bokil'on, Tat'iana (Folder 14: 82)
    - Bokur, Klod (Folder 14: 83)
    - Boldyreva, Elena (Folder 14: 84)
    - Bologov, Nadezhda (Folder 14: 85)
    - Bologovskaia, Natal'ia (Folder 14: 86)
    - Boltushkin, Aleksandr (Folder 14: 87)
    - Borisov, Elena (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Borodina, Ol'ga (Folder 15: 2)
    - Borsuk, Oleg (Folder 15: 3)
    - Bosenko, Konstantin (Folder 15: 4)
    - Bozhenko, Irina (Folder 15: 5)
    - Brad, Aleksandr (Folder 15: 6)
    - Brad, Nikolai (Folder 15: 7)
    - Brainin, Grigorii (Folder 15: 8)
    - Brakgauzen, Igor', von (Folder 15: 9)
    - Braslavskaia, Teodora (Folder 15: 10)
    - Brazhnik, Ekaterina (Folder 15: 11)
    - Brazol', Vladimir (Folder 15: 12)
    - Bretneva, Liudmila (Folder 15: 13)
    - Brilevich, Vladimir (Folder 15: 14)
    - Brofel'dt, Leonid (Folder 15: 15)
    - Bromli, Kirill (Folder 15: 16)
    - Bromli, Ol'ga (Folder 15: 17)
    - Brondstedt, Nara (Folder 15: 18)
    - Bronshtein, Aleksandr (Folder 15: 19)
    - Brovarniuk, Georgii (Folder 15: 20)
    - Brut, Zoia (Folder 15: 21)
    - Brysin, Georgii (Folder 15: 22)
    - Brysin, Petr (Folder 15: 23)
    - Budakovich, Gennadii (Folder 15: 24)
    - Budakovich, Nina (Folder 15: 25)
    - Budanova, Valeriia (Folder 15: 26)
    - Budkevich, Vadim (Folder 15: 27)
    - Budkovskii, Georgii (Folder 15: 28)
    - Bugaevskaia, Svetlana (Folder 15: 29)
    - Buinevich, V. (Folder 15: 30)
    - Bulanov, Gleb (Folder 15: 31)
    - Bulatovich, Rostislav (Folder 15: 32)
    - Bulgakov, Sergei (Folder 15: 33)
    - Bulgakova, Irina (Folder 15: 34)
    - Bulianovskaia, Valentina (Folder 15: 35)
    - Bulianovskii, Evgenii (Folder 15: 36)
    - Bulianovskii, Nikolai (Folder 15: 37)
    - Bulyndina, Nina (Folder 15: 38)
    - Buntovskii, Igor' (Folder 15: 39)
    - Burdon, Marina (Folder 15: 40)
    - Burgasov, Nikolai (Folder 15: 41)
    - Burgasova, Irina (Folder 15: 42)
    - Burnasheva, Nataliia (Folder 15: 43)
    - Burnatsev, Georgii (Folder 15: 44)
    - Burov, Petr (Folder 15: 45)
    - Buryshkin, Vladimir (Folder 15: 46)
    - Buryshkina, Ol'ga (Folder 15: 47)
    - Butakov, Mikhail (Folder 15: 48)
    - Buteneva, Ekaterina (Folder 15: 49)
    - Bulterov, Aleksandr (Folder 15: 50)
    - Bulterov, Nikolai (Folder 15: 51)
    - Bulterova, Vera (Folder 15: 52)
    - Buturlinskii, Nikolai (Folder 15: 53)
    - Butorov, Nikolai (Folder 15: 54)
    - Butorova, Kseniia (Folder 15: 55)
    - Bychkov, Viktor (Folder 15: 56)
    - Bykov, Georgii (Folder 15: 57)
    - Bykov, Konstantin (Folder 15: 58)
    - Bykova, Rozaliia (Folder 15: 59)
    - Bykova, Sofiia (Folder 15: 60)
    - Bylov, Nikolai (Folder 15: 61)
    - Bynina, Liubov' (Folder 15: 62)
    - Byrdina, Alla (Folder 15: 63)
    - Chakhotin, Andrei (Folder 15: 64)
    - Chakhotin, Petr (Folder 15: 65)
    - Chaussonniere, Pascal (Folder 15: 66)
    - Chavchavadze, Irina (Folder 15: 67)
    - Chavchavadze, Nikolai (Folder 15: 68)
    - Chechot, Georgii (Folder 15: 69)
    - Chekomasova, Vera (Folder 15: 70)
    - Chekhovich, Irina (Folder 15: 71)
    - Chelbin, Lev (Folder 15: 72)
    - Chelbina, Liudmila (Folder 15: 73)
    - Cherednikova, Nina (Folder 15: 74)
    - Cheremoeva, Dzhennet (Folder 15: 75)
    - Cherkaskii, Ivan (Folder 15: 76)
    - Cherkasov, Aleksandr (Folder 15: 77)
    - Chermnova, Selima (Folder 15: 78)
    - Cherniakhovskii, Mikhail (Folder 15: 79)
    - Cherniatynskii, Vadim (Folder 15: 80)
    - Cherniavskaia, Irina (Folder 15: 81)
    - Cherniavskii, Sofiia (Folder 15: 82)
    - Chernikova, Galina (Folder 15: 83)
    - Chernitsa, Konstantin (Folder 15: 84)
    - Chernobrovkin, Nikolai (Folder 15: 85)
    - Chernomorov, Sergei (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Chernosvitova, Aleksandra (Folder 16: 2)
    - Chernova, Liudmila (Folder 16: 3)
    - Chernyi, Igor' (Folder 16: 4)
    - Chernykh, Vladimir (Folder 16: 5)
    - Chernyshev-Bezobrazova, Aleksandra (Folder 16: 6)
    - Chernyshev-Bezobrazova, Kira (Folder 16: 7)
    - Chernyshev-Bezobrazova, Ol'ga (Folder 16: 8)
    - Chernyshev-Bezobrazova, Vera (Folder 16: 9)
    - Cherskii, Arkadii (Folder 16: 10)